Benjamin Smith Barton Papers 1789-1815 Mss.B.B284d
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Subject files, ca.1789-1815; 7 boxes; 3.5 linear feet (Box 7-13)
  Notes and manuscripts by Barton or collected by Barton relating to his research in Botany, Indians, Medicine, and Miscellaneous other subjects.
  - Botanical notes and manuscripts
    - "Poem in re Bartram's Garden", n.d.; 1 item (9 p.); Ode to Bartram's garden in verse, comparing nature to city life.
    - Barton, Benjamin Smith
      - "Of the Power of habit of Plants", n.d.; 11 items
      - Botanical Notes #1, 1805 March 23-1806 April 1; 13 items
      - Botanical Notes #2, n.d.; 1 item (7 p.)
      - Botanical Notes #3, n.d.; 18 items
      - Botanical Notes #4, 1812 Sept. 14-1814 Dec. 30; 21 items
      - Botanical Notes #5, 1794 July 3-1808 July 30; 28 items
      - Botanical Notes #6, 1807 Aug.-1813 May; 37 items
      - Botanical Notes #7, 1807 May 22-1812 June 18; 47 items
      - Botanical Notes #8, 1797 Jan. 2-1809 May 17; 19 items
      - Botanical Notes #9, 1805 Oct. 28-1814; 16 items
      - Botanical Notes #10, 1804; 4 items
      - Botanical Notes #11, 1803 May-1811 June 13; 32 items
      - Botanical notes #12, 1810 Sept. 29-1814 Aug.; 52 items
        Notes for Flora Virginica.
      - Botany Course, 1812 June 20; 1 item
      - Chronology of Botanists, ect., See oversized
      - Description of a new North American Plant, See oversized
      - Elements of Botany #1, 1803; 13 items
      - Elements of Botany #2, 1814 Oct. 15; 19 items
      - Geographical Distribution of trees..., 1807 July 8-1809 Aug. 15; 18 items
      - Index pages (botanical), 1811 July 11-n.d.; 21 items
      - Irritability of Plants, n.d.; 1 item
      - Lectures on botany, n.d.; 4 items (31 p.)
      - Lists of plants #1, n.d.; 3 items
      - Lists of plants #2, n.d.; 6 items
      - Michaux, Francois Andre, 1817; 6 items
      - Odorous Vegetables, etc., 1813 Aug. 16-1814 June 16; 18 items
      - Page proofs, etc., n.d.; 9 items
      - Plant Fertilization, etc., n.d.; 7 items
      - Plant Respiration, n.d.; 1 item
      - Potatoes, Coffee, Corn, etc., 1811 Dec. 2; 14 items
      - Prodromus, etc., n.d.; 30 items
      - Sap, n.d.; 1 item (23 p.)
    - Bartonia
      - Holograph of Moses Marshall, n.d.; 1 item
    - Bartram, William
      - An Aquatic Plant, n.d.; 1 item
    - Catalogue of Botanical books, etc. (broadside), n.d.; 1 item
      Botanical notes by Barton on reverse.
    - Catalogue of Sundry Trees and Shrubs, the produce of America, 1 item (4 p.)
    - Catalogue, misc., n.d.; 9 items
    - Individual genera or groups, etc., 1801 June 28-1812 June 13; 37 items
    - Jussieu, Antoine Laurent de, 1748-1836
      - List of plants sent to him, n.d.; 1 item
    - Lambert, J.H.
      - Plants from New Jersey to B. S. Barton, 1807-n.d.; 2 items (15 p.)
        One of the volumes is two pages containing 9 drawings done by Barton dated 1807, Sept. 29.
    - New York Sun
      - Barton and the Holcus bicolor, 1940 June 29; 1 item
    - Pollen, etc., n.d.; 6 items
    - Pursh, Frederick
      - Page proof, 1809 Oct.28; 1item
        Barton's notes on the genus homo on reverse.
    - Sturm, Jacob
      - Nachricht (Advertisement for botany publication), 1796 November; 1 item (4 p.)
    - Weeds, 1807 Nov.-1806 Aug. 1
  - Indian materials, 1 box, 0.5 linear feet
    - Barton, Benjamin Smith
      - Archaelogiae Americana, 1808 Oct. 8-n.d.; 12 items
      - Bruce, Archibald, 1814 Oct. 12; 1 item
      - Fort Pitt, n.d.; 1 item
      - Indian languages, 1 item
        On reverse, a letter to Barton from Mr. Gumpert describing his child's illness dated 1809, Sept. 21.
      - Indian notes, misc., 1812 Sept. 14; 3 items
      - Indian's view of the sun, 1810 June 11-n.d.; 2 items
        Also, a note from A. Paschall seeking medical advice.
      - Journal fragments, 1799 Jan. 5-1799 Feb. 4; 2 items (4 p.)
      - Journal on Tuscaroras, n.d.; 1 item (3 p.)
        Note within folder claims that the journal belongs with 1799 Journal to no. New York in "volumes" series.
      - Kaigana vocabulary note, n.d.; 1 item (1 p.)
      - Kaskaskian Indians, 1 item (1 p.)
      - Mandan word list, 1 item
      - Misc. Indian notes, 1813 Sept. 10-n.d.; 7 items
        Including 2 newspaper articles.
      - New Views, misc. #1, folder 3, n.d.; 6 items
      - New Views, misc. #2, folder 1, 1797-1798; 8 items
      - New Views, misc. #3, folder 1, 1811 May 10-n.d.; 20 items
      - New Views, misc. #3, folder 2, 1786-n.d.; 31 items
      - New Views, misc. #3, folder 3, 1801 Aug.-n.d.; 28 items
      - New Views, misc. #3, folder 4, n.d.; 20 items
      - New Views, misc. #3, folder 5, n.d.; 2 items (9 p.)
      - New Views, misc. #3, folder 6, n.d.; 9 items
      - New Views, misc. #1, folder 1, n.d.; 23 items
      - New Views, misc. #1, folder 2, n.d.; 14 items
      - Note on Indian terms for Pleides, 1812 Aug. 7-n.d.; 2 items
        On reverse, a note from J.M.White requesting endorsement of a bank note.
      - Note on origin of potato, n.d.; 1 item
        Notice of A.P.S. meeting on reverse dated 1807, Nov. 12
      - Peruvian Chronology, etc., n.d.; 11 items
      - Plants cultivated by Indians, 12 items
      - Queries concerning Indians, 2 items
      - Queries on S. American tribes, n.d.; 1 item
      - Queries to Mr. Sargent, 1794 June 4; 1 item
      - Tlascalan notes, n.d.; 1 item
      - Upper New York and Indians, 1795 Oct. 8; 1 item (4 p.)
      - Vocabulary lists (New Views) #1, n.d.; 16 items (20 p.)
      - Vocabulary lists (New Views) #2, n.d.; 17 items (25 p.)
      - Vocabulary lists (New Views) #3, n.d.; 18 items (20 p.)
      - Vocabulary lists (New Views) #4, n.d.; 5 items (6 p.)
      - Vocabulary lists (New Views) #5, n.d.; 6 items (10 p.)
      - Vocabulary, n.d.; 1 item
        On the reverse is a letter from S. Calhoun describing the illness of Mr. Eyling.
    - Bartram, William
      - Seminoles and Cherokees, 1 item (5 p.)
      - Page proofs, misc. notes on certain plants and their use by Indians, 2 items (13p.)
    - Brackenridge, Henry
      - Indian Antiquity, 1813 July 25; 1 item (14 p.); 14 page letter, two blank sheets, discussing Native American antiquity.
    - Burnet, Mr.
      - Choktaw word list, n.d.; 1 item (1 p. fragment)
    - Dunbar, William
      - to Gov. Sergent about Natchez Indians, 1801 Feb. 2; 1 item (1 p.)
    - Dye root used by Wyandot Indians, 1 small packet of material
    - Edwards, A.
      - Esculent Roots, 1809 Oct. 12; 1 item (3 p.)
    - Explanation of the Plate, n.d.; 1 item (3 p.)
    - Fothergill, Anthony, 1732?-1813
      - to George Turner on Choctaws, n.d.; 1 item (short note)
    - Geffard, Mr.
      - American Indians, 1789 May; 1 item (1 p.)
    - Heckewelder, John
      - Indian queries and answers, 2 items (8 p.)
    - On Maize or Indian corn, 1 item (4 p.)
    - Preston, Samuel
      - On the Origin of the Indians, 1804 Dec. 15; 1 item (13 p.)
        Critical comments on Kames' polygenic arguments for origin of Indians and Robertson's and Pennant's theory of dispersal across the Arctic regions. Believes Indians are descendants of "Phoenicians or Tyreans, Egyptians, Jews, and Carthageneans accidentally driven across the Atlantic by the Trade Winds at different Times...," Welsh origins of some also possible. Comparison of cultural traits of circum-Mediterraneans and Indians.
    - Rafinesque, C.S.
      - Osage Vocabulary, 1804; 1 item (2 p.)
    - Remerez, Mr.
      - Mexican vocabulary list, n.d.; 1 item (1 p.)
    - Temple of Talomeco, description, n.d.; 1 item (4 p.)
    - Vocabulary lists, American Indian, 2 items (21 p.)
    - Webster, Mr.
      - Confederacy, 1806 Feb.; 1 item
    - Zeisberger, D.
      - Onondaga Dictionary, 1 item (50 p.)
        The dictionary is initialed J.H. for John Heckewelder who presumably copied the dictionary.
  - Medical notes and manuscripts
    - Barton, Benjamin Smith
      - Address to medical graduates, n.d.; 10 items
      - Advertisement for journal, n.d.; 1 item
      - Cullen's Materia Medica, 1809 Feb. 23-n.d.; 9 items
      - Drug experimentation, n.d.; 1 item
      - Election of the Medical Society, 1809 Feb. 4; 1 item
      - Facts, etc. regarding yellow fever, n.d.; empty folder.
      - Fever from decaying vegetation, n.d.; 1 item (2 p.)
      - Fevers, 1808 Jan. 24-n.d.; 27 items
      - Gout, n.d.; 1 item
      - Materia Medica, misc., n.d.; 3 items (16 p.)
      - Medical notes, misc. #1, 1802 March 1-1813 Feb. 21; 37 items
      - Medical notes, misc. #2, 1814 Nov. 14-n.d.; 21 items
      - Medical notes, misc. #3, 1808 Feb.-1809 March 10; 28 items
      - Medical notes, misc. #4, 1803 June 24-1811 Aug. 16; 2 items (71 p.)
      - Medical notes, misc. #5, 1810 July 5-1811 Feb. 8; 28 items
      - Medical notes, misc. #6, n.d.; 6 items (25 p.)
      - Medical notes, misc. #7, 1799 Feb. 8-1812 Aug. 17; 46 items
      - Medical notes, misc. #8, 1814 Aug. 3-n.d.; 56 items
      - Medical notes, misc. #9, 1808 Sept. 28-1813 Oct. 24; 53 items (70 p.)
      - Page proofs of Cullen's Practice of Physic, n.d.; 1 item (71 p.)
      - Page proofs, cont'd., n.d.; 1 item (111 p.)
      - Patients and experimental use of roots, 1 item (10 p.)
      - Practice of Physic note, n.d.; 1 item (1 p.)
      - Tickets (U. of Pa. Lectures), n.d.; 11 items
      - U. of P. medical professor's resolution, 1803 Feb. 9; 1 item
      - Yellow fever, n.d.; 25 items (34 p.)
    - Barton, William P.C.
      - A case of chronick rheumatism, cured by the mustard-bran-bath, 1809 March 24; 1 item
    - Bogen, John Henry
      - An inaugural essay on the dysentery, n.d.; 1 item (37 p.)
    - College of Physicians
      - Notice of meeting, 1803 Sept. 6-1810 Feb. 6; 2 items
    - Fox, Edward
      - Receipt to Paul Hutchinson for U. of P., 1814-1815; 1 item
    - Hydrophobia, n.d.; 1 item
    - L'Ecole De Medecine de Paris
      - Bulletin, 1804; 1 item (4 p.)
    - Mason, John
      - Origin of fevers, n.d.; 1 item
    - Medical Society of London
      - A List of the Fellows of the Society, 1809; 1 broadside
      - Acknowledgement of discourse, 1809 June 24; 1 broadside
    - Medicine, n.d.; 1 item (17 p.)
    - Meyer, Friedrich Detlef
      - Treatment of yellow fever in St. Thomas, 1804; 1 item (6 p.)
    - Pennsylvania Hospital
      - List of patients, n.d.; 1 item (2 p.)
    - Philadelphia Medical Society
      - Dinner invitation to Barton, 1804 Feb. 16; 1 item
    - Societas Medica Philadelphiensis
      - Certificate of Membership, n.d.; 1 broadside
    - Societe de Medecine de Bordeaux
      - Programme, n.d.; 1 broadside
    - St. Georges, Chevalier
      - Fevers in French Islands and N. America, 1765 ca.; 1 item (11 p.)
    - Venereal disease, n.d.; 1 item
  - Miscellaneous notes and manuscripts
    - Admission cards, 1800 April 25-1809; 11 items
      Admission cards to Barton's lectures.
    - American Linnean Society, 1803 April 5-n.d.; 8 items
      - American Linnean Society certificate, 1803
    - American Philosophical Society
      - Certificates of Membership, 1791 Feb. 14-1794 May 5; 4 items
    - American Philosophical Society, 1812 June 25-1815 March 3; 2 items
    - Barton, Benjamin Smith
      - "Elements" order, n.d.; 1 item
      - "The Studies of Nature..." broadside, n.d.; 1 item
        Handwritten note on reverse, dated 1810 June 1, about specimens that Barton had received from Mr. Yard.
      - Air and Atmosphere notes, 1809 Jan. 22-n.d.; 9 items
      - Alkali and Minerals, 38 items
      - Alligators and Hell-Bender, 1806 March 31-n.d.; 5 items
      - American Antiquarian Society, 1815 Feb. 28; 1 item
      - Appointment, n.d.; 1 item
        Note of Dr. Shippen's support for his appointment to the chair of Materia Medica.
      - Autobiographical note, n.d.; 1 item
      - Bankbook, 1807 April 7-1812 March 16; 1 item
      - Banks, Joseph, 1814 July 3; 1 item
      - Barton, Thomas - Gift., 1809 Jan. 14; 1 item
      - Birch and Small, 1808 July 4; 1 item
      - Birds, 1808 Jan.-n.d.; 23 items
      - Checkbook from Bank of Pennsylvania, n.d.; 1 item
      - Checkbook from Mechanical Bank, n.d.; 1 item
      - Crotulus Horridus, n.d.; 2 items
      - Election, n.d.; 1 item
      - Elephants, n.d.; 31 items
      - Etching, 1810 Jan. 21; 1 item
      - Eulogy on Joseph Priestly, n.d.; 6 items
      - Fossils, 1807 June 17; 1 item
      - German-English Vocabulary, n.d.; 1 item
      - Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1806 Nov. 9; 1 item
      - Insects, n.d.; 17 items
      - Lectures - Natural History and Natural Philosophy, 100 p.
      - Lectures - Natural Knowledge, n.d.; 12 p.
      - Lectures - Zoology, n.d.; 32 p.
      - Linnaeus, Solander, etc., 1811 Nov. 18; 1 item
      - List "To take to Europe", 1815 April; 3 items
        Folder was dated April 1815 although there's no date on any of the three items.
      - Loan, 1809 Feb. 22; 1 item
      - Meteorological Diary, 1789 Jan. 1-1789 May 31; 1 item (10 p.)
      - Mr. Grigg - Death from a dogbite, 1811 March 24; 1 item
      - Natural History, 1810 March-1812 June 2; 6 items
      - Notes - Ammonia, 1807 May 28; 8 items
      - Notes - Astronomy, n.d.; 6 items
      - Notes - Atmosphere and Climate, 1809 June 17; 1 item
      - Notes - Chemistry, 1810 June-1812 Dec. 8; 37 items
      - Notes - Elements of Zoology, n.d.; 12 items
      - Notes - Geology, 1788 May 10-n.d.; 5 items
      - Notes - Lecture, misc. (1 of 3), n.d.; 3 items (30 p).
      - Notes - Lecture, misc. (2 of 3), n.d.; 6 items (13 p.)
      - Notes - Lecture, misc. (3 of 3), n.d.; 46 p.
      - Notes - Mercury, n.d.; 15 p.
      - Notes - misc. (1 of 4), 1807 Aug. 24-1814 June 3; 45 items
      - Notes - misc. (2 of 4), 1753 Aug. 10-1808 Aug. 5; 27 items
      - Notes - misc. (3 of 4), 1814 Dec. 14-n.d.; 37 items
      - Notes - misc. (4 of 4), 1806 Nov.-n.d.; 46 items
      - Notes - Scientific, misc. (1 of 9), 1809 Feb 22-1814 Oct. 29; 61 items
      - Notes - Scientific, misc. (2 of 9), 1807 March 3-1813 Sept.; 55 items
      - Notes - Scientific, misc. (3 of 9), 1796 August 5-1813 Sept. 21; 70 items
      - Notes - Scientific, misc. (4 of 9), 1794 Nov. 4-1809 May; 14 items
      - Notes - Scientific, misc. (5 of 9), 1808 Feb. 25-1812 April 22; 42 items
      - Notes - Scientific, misc. (6 of 9), 1809 July-1814 March 21; 36 items
      - Notes - Scientific, misc. (7 of 9), 1806 Dec. 11-1814 Dec.; 30 items
      - Notes on discourse, 1809 June 13-n.d.; 2 items
      - Notes, Scientific, misc. (8 of 9), 1807 Dec. 11-1812 Feb.; 22 items
      - Notes, Scientific, misc. (9 of 9), 1806 Aug. 9-1810 May 2; 3 items
      - Notes, Travel (Cedar Creek, Virginia), n.d.; 1 item
      - Notes, Travel, n.d.; 6 items
      - Notes, Zoology (1 of 5), 1806 Oct. 1-n.d.; 20 items
      - Notes, Zoology (2 of 5), 1795 Oct. 22-1814 Nov.; 43 items
      - Notes, Zoology (3 of 5), 1805 Jan. 30-1813 Oct.; 52 items
      - Notes, Zoology (4 of 5), 1807 Sept. 20-1813 June 11; 51 items
      - Notes, Zoology (5 of 5), 1807 March 18-1810 Feb.; 26 items
      - Nuttall, Thomas, 1810 April 7; 1 item
      - Oil of Amber, 1803 Feb. 13; 1 item
      - Opium, n.d.; 11 items
      - Opossums (1 of 2), 1806 Aug. 16-1807 March 6; 24 items
      - Opossums (2 of 2), n.d.; 3 items
      - Page Proofs (1 of 4), n.d.; 8 items
      - Page Proofs (2 of 4), n.d.; 10 items
      - Page Proofs (3 of 4), n.d.; 30 items
      - Page Proofs (4 of 4), n.d.; 20 items
      - Pike's Expedition, 1811 May 14; 1 item
      - Plans for fortification, n.d.; 2 items
      - Portrait, 1939 May 16-1939 June 6; 4 items
        Two portraits of Barton and two letters to John Ross Delafield about the portraits.
      - Promissory note, 1811 July 13; 1 item
      - Publications, 1799 June 1; 1 item
      - Receipts
        - Adams, John, and Company. (Printing)
        - American Daily Advertiser (Newspaper)
        - American Philosophical Society. (dues)
        - Ash, Thomas
        - Ashby, Mauzey Q.
        - Ashhurst, Richard
        - Baker, John L
        - Bank of North America (orders to pay)
        - Bank of Pennsylvania (orders to pay)
        - Barrington, C. (almonds, port, ale...)
        - Barton, David R. (clothing and supplies)
        - Barton, Mary. (annuity)
        - Bronson, Enos (Gazette)
        - Brooke, William (medical bill)
        - Brown, Joseph (printing)
        - Brown and Relf (Gazette)
        - Burd, Mr.
        - Campbell, Robert, and Co. (tea)
        - Carrell, John (note)
        - Clempffe, Mr., et al. (debts, printing, medical fees)
        - Cohen, E (rent)
        - Commercial Bank of Pennsylvania (orders to pay)
        - Conrad, John. (Publications, doctor bill)
        - Conyers, Walter (shoes)
        - Cooke, Increase (books)
        - Cooper, William
        - Cox, Gideon (flour tubs)
        - Craige, Seth
        - Crukshank, Joseph
        - Crump, Mr.
        - Cummens, Charles (dressing patients)
        - Dainty, John (printing)
        - De Silver, Thomas. (binding)
        - Dickenson, Abel (printing)
        - Dobson, Judah (publications)
        - Earle, E., and Co. (books)
        - Evans, Edward (binding)
        - Evans, Robert (promissory note)
        - Farmers and Mechanics Bank (orders to pay)
        - Farrandole, William
        - Freemasons - Philadelphia (party-wall)
        - Gatchet, Joseph (removes?)
        - George $8.00
        - Goodwin, John C (hospital)
        - Gorgas, Mr.
        - Grant, Peter (stitching pamphlets)
        - Gray, Joseph
        - Gwathmey, George (doctor's apprentice)
        - Hagenan, John N (note, for imported book)
        - Haines, Ephraim (case with glass door)
        - Hamm, Jacob (smith)
        - Harvey, Mr.
        - Hewat, Mr.
        - Hewson, N (books)
        - Hindman, J
        - Hommann, J C. (piano lessons)
        - Hunter, James (hay)
        - Hyde, George, and Co.
        - Jackson, D
        - Johnson, J
        - Jones, Nathan (boards)
        - Keighler, Jacob
        - Keyser, John (wood)
        - Klack, John
        - Lapsley, William John (carpentry)
        - Lowbee, Edward (apothecary - medicine)
        - McAlpin, J (clothing)
        - Maclure and Robertsons. (portage)
        - McC oy, John. (cleaning)
        - Magnes, R (medicine)
        - Marshall, E
        - Metcalf, Mr. (books)
        - Michaux, Francois Andre (books)
        - Nott, Thomas (framing)
        - Nunes, A J (book)
        - Penn,R
        - Phelan, E (washing, board)
        - Philadelphia, City of (taxes)
        - Postage
        - Redman, Thomas L
        - Richoy, John
        - Riddle, James
        - Rider, Mr. (labor)
        - Rogers, P K
        - Ruggles, Sharman (shoes)
        - Schneider, Henry (tailor)
        - [Sargeant?], K and R
        - Seymour, Joshua H., and William (engraving plates)
        - Shallus, Francis (engraving plates)
        - Shippen, Mr. (for nephew, William)
        - Sim, Mrs.
        - Smith, J R (interest)
        - Smith, Rowland (wood)
        - Snyder, George
        - Sperry and Huffnagh (glass)
        - Stock, John
        - Tanner, James (watch)
        - Tebbs, Mr. (publication)
        - Thomas, Jacob
        - Vaughan, John
        - Wager, Peter (wine)
        - West, Sarah (ground rent)
        - White, J M (bond)
        - Wills, James, and Sons (brushes, vinegar...)
        - Wood, D
        - Woodward, Mr. (publications)
        - Young, John
      - Rush, Benjamin - eulogium, 1813 July 30; 1 item
      - Siren Lacertina (also notes on beavers and wolves), 1807 March-1809 Sept. 3; 18 items
      - Snakes, 1805 Feb. 8-1815 Jan. 13; 43 items
      - Swallows, n.d.; 8 items
      - Travel Journal (2 of 2), 1806 July 4-n.d.; 21 items (42 p.)
      - Travel Journal, 1809-n.d.; 8 items (77 p.)
      - Turkeys, n.d.; 3 items
      - University of Pennsylvania- Lists of students, 1805-1814; 8 items
        Lists of students taking courses in materia medica.
      - University of Pennsylvania, 1808 June 9; 1 item (15 p.)
        Address to medical graduates.
      - Woodhouse, James, n.d.; 1 item
    - Barton, R. R.
      - Thermometrical Observations, 1815 April 5; 1 item
    - Barton, William
      - A dissertation on the freedom of Navigation..., 1802; 1 item (7 p.)
    - Bartram, William
      - "Life and Character of John Bartram", 3 items (2 xeroxes)
    - Bible Society of Philadelphia
      - Circular, 1813 March 15; 1 item
    - Benjamin Smith Barton and Mary Penington
      - Biography (typescript), n.d.; 1 item (2 copies)
    - Book pages, misc., n.d.; 4 items
    - Bookseller's List, n.d.; 1 item
    - Catalogue of Books, Prints, etc. To be Sold at Auction in Philadelphia, n.d.; 1 item (12 p.)
    - Catherine II of Russia
      - Certificate to J. G. E. Heckewelder, 1794 April 1; 1 item
    - Cattell, Seth
      - Promissory note, 1809 Dec. 25; 1 item
    - Christian -Albrecht's - Universitat, Kiel
      - Diploma, 1796; 1 item
    - Cutbush, James
      - "On the Formation & Advantages of Oxygenated Sulphate", 1806; 1 item (6 p.)
    - Eckhardt, George H.
      - Pennsylvania Horticultural Society, 1795 April 15
    - Edinburgh, University of
      - Classes for the different Branches of Education, 1810 Sept. 12; 1 item
    - Edward VI, "The King's Death", n.d.; 1 item
    - "A Sermon occasioned by the Death of Dr. Priestly" (extract), n.d.; 4 items
    - Esculent Nests, n.d.; 1 item (2p.)
    - Estimate of Probable Income, 1804 March 26; 2 items
    - Experiments Made with Arsenic on different animals, 1 item (7p.)
    - Garden Club of America
      - Barton Exhibit, 1937 Jan. 3-1937 Jan.; 15 items
      - Bartoniana, 1937 Jan.; 3 items
    - Heckewelder, J.
      - Description of the Falls of Niagara..., n.d.; 1 item (9 p.)
    - Hobbs, Mr.
      - Notes on squirrels, n.d.; 1 item
    - Hudry, J. A.
      - Seeking medical attention, n.d.; 1 item
    - Kiel
      - Diploma to Benjamin Smith Barton
        Empty. See Christian-Albrechts-Universitat
    - Lindley, Jacob
      - Journal, 1793 May; 1 item (3 p.)
    - Linnean Society of London
      - List of members, 1798; 1 item
    - Literary Societies in Copenhagen, 1811; 1 item
    - Maps, n.d.; 7 items
    - Newspaper clippings, 1809-1813; 5 items
    - Nuttall, Thomas
      - Portrait, n.d.; 1item
    - Of Vegetables Poisons, n.d.; 1 item (5 p.)
    - Peale's Museum, 1813 Nov.; 1 item
    - Penington, Ann
      - Last Will and Testament, 1806 Oct. 24; 1 item
    - Penington, Edward & Son
      - Sugar labels, n.d.; 2 items
    - Pennant, Thomas
      - Advertisement, 1930; 1 item
    - Pennsylvania Hospital
      - Admission form, n.d.; 1 item
    - Perkins, Jacob
      - Invention, 1810 Nov. 26; 1 item (5p.)
    - Philadelphia
      - Statement of Deaths, 1815; 1 item
    - Poems, inc. "Damon and Melibeus to the Rev. Mr. Richard Peters of Phila...", 1 item (22 p.)
    - Promissory note and request for attendance on reverse, 1810 April 29-1810 May 16; 1 item
    - Prospectus
      - D'une traduction en François de l'ouvrage de Mr. De Zimmermann, n.d.; 1 item (7 p.)
    - Rittenhouse, David
      - Meteor, n.d.; 1 item
    - Roume, Philippe Rose
      - Avertissement Sur La pronunciation Des Negres, ca.1800-1801; 1 item
    - Royal Jennerian Society
      - Dinner notice, 1803 May 17; 1 item (broadside)
    - Royal Society of London
      - In appreciation of Barton's opossum work, 1807 April 13; 1 item
    - Shippen, William
      - Memoir, n.d.; 1 item (4p.)
    - Spafford's Patent, 1815 Feb. 18; 2 items
    - Spalding, Lyman
      - Bill of Mortality, 1811; 1 item
    - Thompson, Dr.
      - Trip through New Hampshire, 1809 Feb. 21; 1 item (4 p.)
    - To the Honourable the Senate and House of Representatives of the State..., 1 item
    - United States Army
      - General Orders, n.d.; 1 item
    - United States President